PERIOD

Summary

Senior QA/Test Analyst with Tata Consultancy Services Limited since 5 years and 9 months where I have worked with US client in Retail business domain. CVS RxConnect is drug dispensing software system, enabling a pharmacy to fulfil the needs of prescription filling and drug dispensing activities. It is based on the Onsite and Offshore model. This system permits distribution of the prescription filling activities, enabling the pharmacy to complete the process in a shorter period of time. The system scales, supporting a single retail pharmacy up through an enterprise organization consisting of multiple pharmacies dispersed across a large geographically area. Through all the learning experiences I have gained expertise in following areas: Â To work in various SDLC life cycle Interacting with client and different team for requirement gathering and analysis. Preparing Test Plans, TCDR Plans for Projects, BSR's. Effort Estimations, review of Business Requirement Creation, Execution of Test cases Have knowledge on PL/Experienced in functional, negative, regression, system integration (SIT), acceptance (UAT) testing, replication activity on maintenance builds Testing software programs to compare to specifications and documentation. Identifying, analyzing defects, questionable functions, errors, program functionality, outputs, online screens, and content. Creation of test status reports

Certifications: Oracle DB Certification

Experience

Period

December 2009 to February 2010 Bickford Senior Living

Position Test Analyst

October 2009 to Current Tata Consultancy Services

- I am an associate with Tata Consultancy Services Limited since 5 years and 2 months where I have worked with US client in Retail business
- CVS RxConnect is drug dispensing software system, enabling a pharmacy to fulfil the needs of prescription filling and drug dispensing activities.
- It is based on the Onsite and Offshore model.
- This system permits distribution of the prescription filling activities, enabling the pharmacy to complete the process in a shorter period of time.
- The system scales, supporting a single retail pharmacy up through an enterprise organization consisting of multiple pharmacies dispersed across a large geographically area.
- Through all the learning experiences I have gained expertise in following areas: To work in various SDLC lifecycle Interacting with client and different team for requirement gathering and analysis.
- Preparing Test Plans, TCDR Plans for Projects, BSR's.
- Effort Estimations, review of Business Requirements Creation, Execution of Test cases Have knowledge on PL/SQL Experienced in functional, negative, regression, system integration (SIT), acceptance (UAT) testing, replication activity on maintenance builds Testing software programs to compare to specifications and documentation.
- Identifying, analysing defects, questionable functions, errors, program functionality, outputs, online screens, and content.
- Creation of test status reports Period Since February 2010 Client Name CVS/Pharmacy Vertical Retail Responsibilities Gathering requirements in-detail from Business Specification Document, Use Cases and PRF Understanding the HIPPA 2 Standards.
- Understanding the NCPDP D.0 and NCPDP 5.1 Standards.
- Understanding the functionality of RxConnect and Speciality Systems.
- Creation of Test Plan Document Creation of Test Scenarios Creation & Execution of Test Cases Review of Test Cases Training team members.
- Conducting Integration Testing/System Testing/UAT Logging\Tracking of the Defects in the Quality Center and Team Track.
- To perform Root Cause Analysis of Defect Providing Estimates of slotted projects, defect and CRs in a Release.
- Creation of Test Status Reports, TCRD Plan Project Experience Release No. Content/Phase Roles and Responsibility Release 4 PSI2
 Evolution As a team member was actively involved in test case creation and execution in Integration Testing, System Testing and UAT
 Release 5 Medicare B Was involved completely from creation of test cases and execution in IT /ST/UAT. Was key member of Release 5
 Team
- Release 6 EPCS, PR & OK Track Owner of EPCS, PR/OK in R6, Conduct PRG, Requirement discussions, Daily and weekly Status
 Reports, Managing Testing activities of release also mentoring the fresher in the team Release 7 We Care Work Flow (PSI 2) SME of
 FAX, QR and POS tracks in R7, Leading the test case development and review group for these tracks.
- Worked as module lead and given multiple demos of the application and functionality to client.
- Release 10 Integrated Speciality Program Control Worked as a Test Analyst, took complete owner ship for Test Case development and review process, conduct PRG, did RCA & effort estimations for several CRs and Defects.
- Conduct WSR and all IT and ST test entrance and exit meetings.
- Release 15 PAE, PhA, TCA, Rx Web Services Worked as a Test Lead for release 15, took complete ownership of this release from test.
- Conducted sessions to explain business requirements to the team
- Drove test case development and execution.
- Release 19 Prescriber Enhancement, EDWS, PCPS Working as a Test Lead for release 19, owing the complete release from test
 perspective.
- Conducting sessions to explain business requirement to the team.
- Driving test case development executing.

- Also reporting test status to customer.
- While working in the project has gained a good knowledge of the following sub modules: Application Management (App Options) Rx
 Processing DUR Third Party management Retail Pricing T-Log Batch Interfaces Login and Security CSI Offline Hardware Intel Pentium 4,
 Thin client Neoware Operating System Windows, SUSE Linux Languages JAVA/J2EE Supporting Tools HP QC/QTP, PL/SQL
 Developer, Team Track, SharePoint, SVN, TOAD.

October 2009 to February 2010 Tata Consultancy Services it/4 Raytown , STATE Technology Java

 Training Conducted Year Title Presented to Location Organised by 2009 Functional and Technical Sessions about different functionalities & testing standards. RxConnect Trainees Gurgaon Tata Consultancy Services 2012 Training on FAX, QR and POS system TCS Associates Woonsocket Tata Consultancy Services 2013 Training on complete work flow of RxConnect TCS Associates Woonsocket Tata Consultancy Services 2013 Training on Specialty and Enterprise Systems TCS Associates Woonsocket Tata Consultancy Services.

Education

Bachelor Of Technology: May 2009

S.R.M Institute of Science and Technology Computer Science and Engineering

Personal Information

Date of Birth July 10 th 1986 Sex Male Nationality Indian Marital Status Married Date of Joining October 26th 2009 Designation IT Analyst Location Woonsocket, Rhode Island

Skills

Analyst, Hardware, content, Client, CVS, documentation, Driving, FAX, Functional, HP, Intel, J2EE, JAVA, Linux, Logging, Managing, meetings, mentoring, SharePoint, Windows, Enterprise, Operating System, Developer, PL/SQL, Pentium 4, POS, prescription filling, PR, Pricing, QTP, Quality, reporting, Requirement, Retail, Scheme, SDLC, Testing software, Specification, system integration, TOAD, Work Flow Additional Information

Personal Details Date of Birth July 10 th 1986 Sex Male Nationality Indian Marital Status Married Date of Joining October 26th 2009
 Designation IT Analyst Location Woonsocket, Rhode Island